<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Siddhartha S. Srinivasa</title>
    <description>Research notes, papers, and robot videos</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 16:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 16:46:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing Good Reviews</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reviewing papers is one of the most important roles of an academic. But yet, we provide surprisingly little guidance to our reviewers on the &lt;em&gt;tone&lt;/em&gt; of their reviews. I tried to capture some of my thoughts in this email I sent to my reviewers when I ran RSS 2017.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear X,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, again, for serving as a reviewer for RSS 2017!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reviewers are the life-blood of a conference. Your high quality reviews are critical not only for the authors but also for me and for the continued success of RSS. I know you have a lot of experience reviewing, so I will keep this very short and specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like your reviews to be compassionate, constructive, and scholarly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compassionate&lt;/strong&gt;: invert your position and ask yourself how you’d feel if you received your review. If it makes your blood boil, take a break, and revise your review.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constructive&lt;/strong&gt;: I’d like us to believe that every paper has a best paper award winner hidden in it. Your role is to guide the author to reveal it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scholarly&lt;/strong&gt;: cite your sources, do not make claims like &lt;em&gt;“I do not feel this is true”&lt;/em&gt; [your feelings matter to me, but probably not to science]. Do not hawk your viewpoint. And please, absolutely no ad hominem attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a reviewer, your role is to comment on the paper’s quality to help the program committee reach an informed decision. So, please refrain from saying things like &lt;em&gt;“This paper should be rejected from RSS”&lt;/em&gt; in the main body of the review. You’re welcome to add it to the private comments to the committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I am sure that if you try hard [or sometimes not that hard] to investigate the true identity of your authors, you would likely be able to do it [with high probability]. But, please do not use that as grounds for rejection. Instead of saying &lt;em&gt;“I think that the author of this paper is Joe Biden, and this looks a lot like Joe’s 2015 paper”&lt;/em&gt;, just say &lt;em&gt;“Here are the ways this paper is similar to Joe Biden’s 2015 paper”&lt;/em&gt;. In a similar vein, do not punish authors for not citing non peer reviewed content [like arXiv or workshop papers].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Area Chairs and I will be monitoring your reviews and providing you some feedback as this unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy reviewing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact me if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conflicts-of-interest&quot;&gt;Conflicts of Interest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the usual conflict rules, I’d recommend another simple rule: if you feel like you cannot comment on the paper in an unbiased manner, decline to review it. I often find people &lt;em&gt;vested&lt;/em&gt; in a research topic to be the worst reviewers, digging in stubbornly to their viewpoint and refusing to give other ideas a fair listen. The more knowledgable you are, the more &lt;em&gt;enlightened&lt;/em&gt; you ought to be about other viewpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rapoports-rules-of-criticism-as-stated-by-dennet&quot;&gt;Rapoport’s Rules of Criticism as stated by Dennet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’d like to leave you with perhaps the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rapoport%27s_Rules&quot;&gt;succinct summary&lt;/a&gt; on how to compose a critical commentary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “&lt;em&gt;Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You should list any points of agreement (especially if they are not matters of general or widespread agreement).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You should mention anything you have learned from your target.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Only then are you permitted to say so much as a word of rebuttal or criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/18/writing-good-reviews</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/18/writing-good-reviews</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Tangled Web, Slightly Untangled</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally updated my website to the 21st century, and decided to go full Computer Scientist on it.
I was looking for something that was full-featured (&lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathjax.org/&quot;&gt;math&lt;/a&gt;), 
methodical to update (&lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;), and customizable (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fonts.google.com/&quot;&gt;fonts&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having rewritten the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rss2017.lids.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;RSS 2017&lt;/a&gt; website from scratch (later enhanced by the incomparable &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianhou.com/&quot;&gt;Brian Hou&lt;/a&gt;), I developed a fondness for &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as my base engine. Infinitely flexible, Jekyll empowered us to generate the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rss2017.lids.mit.edu/program/detailed/&quot;&gt;proceedings&lt;/a&gt; by piping data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmt3.research.microsoft.com/&quot;&gt;CMT&lt;/a&gt; seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edwardtufte.com/&quot;&gt;Edward Tufte’s&lt;/a&gt; work, especially his advice to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Tufte&quot;&gt;maximize data-ink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, so the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Tufte&quot;&gt;Tufte Jekyll theme&lt;/a&gt; was a natural layout choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hosted the site source code in a private GitHub repo. Now there were several ways to push the &lt;em&gt;built&lt;/em&gt; site out to the world. I considered writing a &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;(https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks)&quot;&gt;git post-receive hook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to pipe the site content to the UW CSE web server (works quite well for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://personalrobotics.cs.washington.edu/&quot;&gt;lab website&lt;/a&gt;), but finally decided on something much simpler: &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/adding-a-remote/&quot;&gt;point&lt;/a&gt; my public &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt; repository to the built site (remember to add an empty &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.nojekyll&lt;/code&gt; file), and let GitHub automatically build and host the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I setup a &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_301&quot;&gt;301 redirect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; from my UW CSE site to my GitHub pages public site. Now I had a stable and working pipeline. Finally, I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodrobot.ai/&quot;&gt;buy a domain&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com/&quot;&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;, and secured it via SSL certificates from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl/&quot;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/18/an-untangled-web</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/18/an-untangled-web</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
